<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The COG Catholic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The COG Catholic</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 20:40:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/page/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Books That Led Me to the Catholic Church</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/top-5-books-that-led-me-to-the-catholic-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 20:40:20 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/top-5-books-that-led-me-to-the-catholic-church/</guid>
      <description>While there is only one path to God &amp;ndash; through Jesus Christ Our Lord &amp;ndash; there are many paths to his Church. These paths are oftentimes paved with books.&#xA;In my case, God used certain writings to help me overcome my particular intellectual and spiritual roadblocks.&#xA;Not everyone has my background, my roadblocks. Not each book that meant something to me will mean something to you. God&amp;rsquo;s ways of reaching our hearts and minds are specially tailored to every person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Neither Cold Nor Hot&#34; -- The Real Lesson of Lukewarm Laodicea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/neither-cold-nor-hot-the-real-lesson-of-lukewarm-laodicea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:05:20 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/neither-cold-nor-hot-the-real-lesson-of-lukewarm-laodicea/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to our religious faith, we all know it’s better to be on fire than to be lukewarm.&#xA;We ask the Holy Spirit to &amp;ldquo;enkindle in us the fire of your love.&amp;rdquo; If we cool off &amp;ndash; if we don&amp;rsquo;t stay &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; we risk quenching the Spirit (1 Thessalonians 5:19).&#xA;It would seem that if cold is the opposite of hot, then to be spiritually lukewarm is better than being spiritually cold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Early Witness on &#34;Going to Heaven&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/an-early-witness-on-going-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 06:01:52 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/an-early-witness-on-going-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>I remember Garner Ted Armstrong, who believed in what others call &amp;ldquo;soul sleep,&amp;rdquo; offering a &amp;ldquo;$10,000 cashier&amp;rsquo;s check&amp;rdquo; to anyone who could find in the Bible a reference to &amp;ldquo;going to heaven&amp;rdquo; when we die.&#xA;Of course, he never surrendered that money, because the Bible nowhere says the words, &amp;ldquo;We go to heaven when we die,&amp;rdquo; or anything else equally explicit.&#xA;The problem with this challenge is the assumption that every Christian teaching must be stated plainly in the Bible for anyone to simply read and understand and believe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Will Your Resurrection Body Be Like?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/what-will-your-resurrection-body-be-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:59:26 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/what-will-your-resurrection-body-be-like/</guid>
      <description>Due to popular misconceptions, consider this a quick Catholic review of the doctrine of resurrection:&#xA;Your eternal reward after this life is not for your soul to leave the body and go to heaven. Neither is it, if you die in mortal sin, for your soul to descend into the fiery pits of hell.&#xA;That’s not to say heaven or hell aren&amp;rsquo;t your ultimate destinations—they are—but not without your body: the same body in which you are reading this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Accept Mary as Our Mother?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/should-we-accept-mary-as-our-mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 05:57:31 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/should-we-accept-mary-as-our-mother/</guid>
      <description>Mary comes to the aid of her Son Jesus in a flashback scene from The Passion of the Christ. Mary is a big deal in the Catholic Church, not only because she is Jesus’ mom, but because she is our mom — your mom and mine. Not in a figurative sense, but in a real sense.&#xA;“No way,” I might have argued before my conversion. “My parents would have something to say about that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Bible Brought Me to Bacon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/how-the-bible-brought-me-to-bacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:55:39 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/how-the-bible-brought-me-to-bacon/</guid>
      <description>Bacon is a special gift from God &amp;ndash; one of the tasty ways by which he tells us, “I love you.”&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a Bible verse for that, but I&amp;rsquo;m convinced.&#xA;In my case, bacon has been a healthful &amp;ldquo;diet food.&amp;rdquo; With its optimal fat-to-protein ratio, it played a role in my losing 40 pounds in three months. It was part of my dietary strategy &amp;ndash; along with intermittent fasting &amp;ndash; to reverse my type 2 diabetes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Your Best-Ever Feast of Tabernacles Is Missing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/what-your-best-feast-of-tabernacles-ever-is-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 05:51:31 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/what-your-best-feast-of-tabernacles-ever-is-missing/</guid>
      <description>This post is for current &amp;ldquo;Church of God&amp;rdquo; members preparing to attend the Feast of Tabernacles, a religious festival I observed for close to 30 years before I became Catholic.&#xA;Every COG sermon I’ve heard about how to have the best-ever Feast of Tabernacles offers the same advice: commit to serving others.&#xA;Be an usher! Be a parking lot attendant (wave those orange cones)! Help organize and decorate the meeting hall!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Changing Life Forms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/on-changing-life-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 05:49:23 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/on-changing-life-forms/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick reply to Jeff, who commented on my guest post entitled &amp;ldquo;Bill Watson&amp;rsquo;s Doctrine of &amp;lsquo;Changing Life Forms&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; at the Banned by HWA blog.&#xA;I had taken issue with Bill (a Church of God International minister and proponent of &amp;ldquo;soul sleep&amp;rdquo;), who claims that people who believe in the immortality of the human soul don&amp;rsquo;t really believe people die, but instead merely &amp;ldquo;change life forms.&amp;rdquo; (If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this reply, read the original post and his comments first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons COGs Are Not Christian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/5-reasons-cogs-are-not-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 05:45:38 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/5-reasons-cogs-are-not-christian/</guid>
      <description>Can we apply the label &amp;ldquo;Christian&amp;rdquo; to the various COGs in the Armstrong tradition, such as the United Church of God (UCG); Church of God, a Worldwide Association (COGWA); Church of God International (CGI); Intercontinental Church of God (ICG); and all the rest?&#xA;We surely agree that the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints (think Mormons) and The Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society (think Jehovah&amp;rsquo;s Witnesses) are not Christian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Let the Bible Interpret the Bible?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/should-we-let-the-bible-interpret-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 05:27:49 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/should-we-let-the-bible-interpret-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>How often I&amp;rsquo;ve heard growing up: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t interpret the Bible! Let the Bible interpret the Bible!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;This is not unique to my background. It&amp;rsquo;s a common refrain in Fundamentalist Christian circles. Yet few seem to catch the irony that, amongst all who say this, there are so many different, contradictory beliefs about what Scripture means.&#xA;The statement is absurd on its face, of course. The Bible interprets the Bible? That&amp;rsquo;s like saying a book reads itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Says Death Is Like Sleep - Heres Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/the-bible-says-death-is-like-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:10:16 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/the-bible-says-death-is-like-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Funerals are sobering because each one is a &amp;ldquo;wake-up&amp;rdquo; call to remind us we will all &amp;ldquo;fall asleep.&amp;rdquo; And that sleep will fall upon us sooner than we tend to think.&#xA;Most people understand perfectly well what we mean by &amp;ldquo;falling asleep in death.&amp;rdquo; And when the Bible describes death in terms of &amp;ldquo;sleep,&amp;rdquo; most people don&amp;rsquo;t read too much into it.&#xA;But some do.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Soul sleep&amp;rdquo; For close to 30 years in Armstongism, I was taught that the reason the Bible frequently describes death as &amp;ldquo;sleep&amp;rdquo; is to indicate that our souls will be utterly out of commission, turned off and tuned out, devoid of all awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does God Alone Have Immortality? (A Failed Prooftext)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/does-god-alone-have-immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 05:32:54 -0500</pubDate><author>thecogcatholic@outlook.com (Darren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/blog/does-god-alone-have-immortality/</guid>
      <description>Does the Bible explicitly deny that human beings were created with immortal souls?&#xA;The COGs teach what some call &amp;ldquo;soul sleep,&amp;rdquo; an accurate label but one generally not embraced by COGs themselves. They teach that when we sleep in death, the soul dies along with the body so that we have no conscious interaction with reality. The &amp;ldquo;spirit in man&amp;rdquo; experiences absolutely nothing, utter darkness, until the resurrection. They believe both body and soul are mortal.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
